{
  "questionList":{
    "question1":[
      {
        "id":1,
        "question":"From the 16th century onward, the speed of a ship was measured by what English invention?",
        "option1":"Recorder",
        "option2":"Knot",
        "option3":"Log",
        "answer":"Log"
      },
      {
        "id":2,
        "question":"Which shadow clock consists of a straight base with a raised crosspiece at one end?",
        "option1":"Sundial",
        "option2":"Timeball",
        "option3":"Astrolable",
        "answer":"Sundial"
      },
      {
        "id":3,
        "question":"What can you call a heavy snow that is not quite a blizzard?",
        "option1":"Skift",
        "option2":"Onding",
        "option3":"Sleet",
        "answer":"Skift"
      },
      {
        "id":4,
        "question":"Which of these words refers to ice newly formed in cracks, holes, or surface puddles of other ice?",
        "option1":"Glimmer",
        "option2":"Cerise",
        "option3":"Tortoni",
        "answer":"Glimmer"
      },
      {
        "id":5,
        "question":"Who invented electric light bulb?",
        "option1":"Bell",
        "option2":"Edison",
        "option3":"Newton",
        "answer":"Edison"
      },
      {
        "id":6,
        "question":"In which century bicycle invented?",
        "option1":"1600s",
        "option2":"1800s",
        "option3":"1700s",
        "answer":"1800s"
      },
      {
        "id":7,
        "question":"Who invented telephone?",
        "option1":"Alexandar Graham Bell",
        "option2":"Benjiman Franklin",
        "option3":"Michael Faradey",
        "answer":"Alexandar Graham Bell"
      },
      {
        "id":8,
        "question":"Which of these is an instrument that makes distant objects appear bigger?",
        "option1":"Battery",
        "option2":"Telescope",
        "option3":"Microphone",
        "answer":"Telescope"
      },
      {
        "id":9,
        "question":"What were the first steam engines used for?",
        "option1":"Powering tractors",
        "option2":"Driving trains",
        "option3":"Pumping water out of mines",
        "answer":"Pumping water out of mines"
      },
      {
        "id":10,
        "question":"What were the world's first wheels used for?",
        "option1":"In toys",
        "option2":"To pull carts",
        "option3":"To help potters shape clay",
        "answer":"To help potters shape clay"
      },
      {
        "id":11,
        "question":"What is the PH of H2O?",
        "option1":"6",
        "option2":"7",
        "option3":"8",
        "answer":"7"
      },
      {
        "id":12,
        "question":"Which of the following gas is reduced in the reduction process?",
        "option1":"Hydrogen",
        "option2":"Oxygen",
        "option3":"Helium",
        "answer":"Hydrogen"
      },
      {
        "id":13,
        "question":"Which of the following compound is mainly used in hand sanitizer?",
        "option1":"Aldehyde",
        "option2":"Ketone",
        "option3":"Alcohol",
        "answer":"Alcohol"
      },
      {
        "id":14,
        "question":"What is the S.I unit of frequency?",
        "option1":"Hertz",
        "option2":"Meter",
        "option3":"Second",
        "answer":"Hertz"
      },
      {
        "id":15,
        "question":"Which of the following gland is present in the human mouth?",
        "option1":"Gonads",
        "option2":"Salivary",
        "option3":"Pituitary",
        "answer":"Salivary"
      },
      {
        "id":16,
        "question":"Name the gland which is present above our kidneys?",
        "option1":"Gonads",
        "option2":"Pituitary",
        "option3":"Adrenal",
        "answer":"Adrenal"
      },
      {
        "id":17,
        "question":"What is the basic unit of our neural system?",
        "option1":"Neuron",
        "option2":"Neutron",
        "option3":"Nucleon",
        "answer":"Neuron"
      },
      {
        "id":18,
        "question":"What is the color of SO2 gas?",
        "option1":"Blue",
        "option2":"Colorless",
        "option3":"Grey",
        "answer":"Colorless"
      },
      {
        "id":19,
        "question":"What is the S.I unit of electric charge?",
        "option1":"Ampere",
        "option2":"Ohm",
        "option3":"Coulomb",
        "answer":"Coulomb"
      },
      {
        "id":20,
        "question":"How many carbon atoms are present in heptane?",
        "option1":"6",
        "option2":"7",
        "option3":"8",
        "answer":"7"
      },
      {
        "id":21,
        "question":"What is the atomic number of phosphorus?",
        "option1":"15",
        "option2":"14",
        "option3":"13",
        "answer":"15"
      },
      {
        "id":22,
        "question":"Name the non-metals which have high melting and boiling point?",
        "option1":"Gallium",
        "option2":"Lead",
        "option3":"Diamond",
        "answer":"Diamond"
      },
      {
        "id":23,
        "question":"ame the part of the body on which coronavirus affects the most?",
        "option1":"Eyes",
        "option2":"Lungs",
        "option3":"Heart",
        "answer":"Lungs"
      },
      {
        "id":24,
        "question":"Name the part of the eye on which image is formed?",
        "option1":"Cornea",
        "option2":"Lens",
        "option3":"Optical nerves",
        "answer":"Cornea"
      },
      {
        "id":25,
        "question":"Which device is used for measuring air pressure?",
        "option1":"Barometer",
        "option2":"Voltmeter",
        "option3":"Ammeter",
        "answer":"Barometer"
      },
      {
        "id":26,
        "question":"What is the scientific name of frog?",
        "option1":"Homo sapiens",
        "option2":"Felis catus",
        "option3":"Anura",
        "answer":"Anura"
      },
      {
        "id":27,
        "question":"Who discovered the x-rays?",
        "option1":"Wilhelm roentgen",
        "option2":"Faraday",
        "option3":"Hertz",
        "answer":"Wilhelm roentgen"
      },
      {
        "id":28,
        "question":"Who discovered the radioactivity?",
        "option1":"Hertz",
        "option2":"Henri Becquerel",
        "option3":"Faraday",
        "answer":"Henri Becquerel"
      },
      {
        "id":29,
        "question":"Name the metal which is easily cut by a simple knife?",
        "option1":"Lead",
        "option2":"Mercury",
        "option3":"Sodium",
        "answer":"Sodium"
      },
      {
        "id":30,
        "question":"The ratio of a mass concentration of species A to the total mass density of the mixture is known as?",
        "option1":"Mole fraction",
        "option2":"Concentration",
        "option3":"Mass Fraction",
        "answer":"Mass Fraction"
      },
      {
        "id":31,
        "question":"Which device is used for measuring air pressure?",
        "option1":"Barometer",
        "option2":"Voltmeter",
        "option3":"Ammeter",
        "answer":"Barometer"
      }
      ]
  }
}
